

Joana Sánchez

Data Analyst

ABOUT ME

Curious and passionate junior in Data Analytics, with experience in Excel, SQL and Tableau.

My background is in Textile Design and Education which enabled me to develop soft skills such as communication, problem solving, critical thinking, patience and building trust and relationships.

Programming has sparked my interest lately and for the last year I finally decided to make a career shift into Data Analytics.

I got immersed in multiple courses online in SQL, Tableau and Excel and now I am ready to make the professional leap.

I have lived in multiple cities in Mexico and the past 5 years I lived in Stockholm, Sweden, which helped me enforce my ability to adapt and tackle unexpected problems. Now my home is in Los Angeles and really excited to discover new challenges in the city.

Currently looking for Junior roles in Data Analytics and seeking to leverage skills and experience to guide business decisions.

CONTACT DETAILS

Joana P Sánchez Martínez

joana.sanchez.mtz@gmail.com Los Angeles, 90066 Driving License **C**

Visa status **L2**

WEBSITES

joanasn.github.io/ www.linkedin.com/in/joanasn

SKILLS

SQL Tableau Excel Adobe Design

LANGUAGE

Spanish •••••
English •••••
Swedish ••••

EDUCATION

Education

Stockholm, Sweden 2021-2022

Textile Design

Puebla, Mexico 2008-2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Freelance

Remote (March 2022 - Present)

- Data collection and analysis
- Manipulating, cleansing and analyzing data using queries in PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL, Oracle Developer
- Translate data into visualizations using Tableau- Data collection and analysis
- Manipulating, cleansing and analyzing data using queries in PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL, Oracle Developer

Translate data into visualizations using Tableau

Skills: HTML5 · Microsoft Visual Studio Code · Data Analysis · Tableau · Oracle SQL Developer · Microsoft SQL Server · SQL

Teacher Assistant - Montessoriförskolan Solvändan

Stockholm, Sweden (August 2021 – March 2022)

Supported the lead Montessori teacher with the daily activities. Mantained the Montessori classroom culture, engaged students with the Montessori material and assisted when required. Had as priority to act proactively and with an efficient and quick communication with the leading teacher. Supervised free play activities. Assisted in preparation of activities regarding the needs from the students.

Administrative Assistant - Prosalus AB

Stockholm, Sweden (September 2018 – August 2021)
Management of office activities of an administrative nature.
Among other things, management of updates in social media and advertising.